Great work today, everyone.
那么大家今天辛苦了！
-Cheers!
-干杯！
Alcohol tastes great after a successful labyrinth raid.
攻略完迷宫喝的酒果然超好喝的
Glad you like it.
你喜欢就好
Is alcohol really that good?
酒真的有那么好喝吗？
If you're curious,
好奇的话
why not take a sip?
要不要喝几口看看呀？
I've never heard that Homunculi can drink.
好像没听说过人造人可以喝酒
Is this okay?
这样没问题吗？
I really want to try…
-好想喝喝看 -好吧 喝一点应该没关系吧
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
It takes a while to get used to the taste.
我想也是啦 一下子很难习惯吧
Why did you make me try it then?
那您为什么要劝我喝喝看呢？
To see your reaction, of course.
因为这样才能看到你那种反应啊
It gets better after a few tries.
只要多喝几次 就会渐渐觉得好喝了
Enough about that.
好啦 先不谈这件事了
You seem to be getting quite close to Lilia and Lily.
你最近好像跟莉莉亚她们走得很近耶
I think we're about the same as we were before.
我觉得跟以前差不多啊
Really?
真的吗？
What do you think, Luna?
露娜觉得呢？
Hey. Don't drag Luna into this.
喂 别把露娜拉下水啊
I think you guys are close too.
我也觉得你们的感情很好
Did that one sip get her drunk?
刚才那一口该不会害她醉了吧？
That's not it.
没有啦
They're not our clan members,
她们虽然不是我们战团的成员
but they helped us a lot too.
但她们也帮了我们很多忙吧
So,
所以我只是担心我们 有没有给她们添麻烦罢了
So, it's not a relationship beyond friendship?
所以你们不是超越伙伴的关系吧？
Not at all.
完全不是
Then,
那么…
would you consider that kind of relationship with me?
你要跟我成为那种关系吗？
Are you drunk?
你是喝醉了吗？
Maybe.
或许吧
I've told you this before.
我之前应该也说过了
It's not something I'd consider at the moment.
我暂时不会考虑那种事
Raiding labyrinths is the most important thing for me at this time.
现在对我来说最重要的就是攻略迷宫
So, I'm not considering
所以现阶段
that kind of relationship with anyone right now.
我不考虑跟任何人成为那种关系
That means we have to hurry up and settle all the matters.
那就得赶紧把这些事全都解决呢
Which means
也就是说
Master isn't seeing anyone right now?
主人现在没有交往对象吧？
Yes, that's right.
没错
Is something the matter?
怎么了吗？
Being with Master
跟主人在一起时
always makes me very happy.
总是让我非常开心
My heart can't help but feel warm.
内心也会不禁变得很温暖
So, I want to be with Master forever.
所以我也想永远和主人在一起
Is… Is that so?
什么？这样啊
Rud, you're rather popular.
路德 你很受欢迎嘛
Shut up.
吵死了
Um,
那个…
do you want some water?
你要喝水吗？
Luna! Are you okay?
喂 露娜
I feel drained…
总觉得今天特别疲惫
Huh? What?
什么？怎么会？
Lilia?
莉莉亚？
Rud. Welcome back.
路德 欢迎回来
Wait, why are you sleeping on my bed?
等等 你为什么睡在我的床上啊？
I had something I wanted to check on,
我有事想确认一下
so I asked Marius to let me come in and wait for you.
所以就拜托玛里乌斯让我进来等你
Hold the fort until I get back.
那就麻烦你顾房间了
I guess I was more tired than I thought.
结果今天好像比想象中还累
I see.
原来如此
So, what did you need to talk to me about?
那你是想跟我确认什么事？
It's about Lily.
是关于莉莉今天的改变
She worked really hard today, didn't she?
那孩子今天不是很努力吗？
Yes.
是啊
Lily performed better than I expected.
莉莉比我想象得还能干
To be honest, she surprised me.
老实说我也吓了一跳
She's always been a kid who can do anything if she keeps cool.
其实她只要保持冷静就能做得很好
You're twins, after all.
毕竟你们是双胞胎
It's not like there's a huge gap in your abilities.
在能力方面本来就不会落差太大
Lily's working really hard.
莉莉真的很努力
She's trying to change, little by little.
一点一点地努力改变
Though maybe she overdid it today. She collapsed from exhaustion.
虽然今天好像努力过头 一回来就累瘫了
What's wrong with you?
怎么了？
What do you think about change?
话说啊 你怎么看待改变这件事？
Don't you find it scary?
不会觉得很可怕吗？
Well,
这个嘛
I actually don't like change much either.
我其实也不太喜欢改变
Especially recently,
尤其是最近
when Avancia started to change,
像是阿凡锡亚开始改变时
I felt like keeping things the same would be better.
有时我会想 是不是保持原样比较好
I think many people in town probably share the same thought as me.
我想镇上应该 有很多人跟我有一样的想法
Even now, I'm not sure if what I'm doing is right.
就算到了现在
But sometimes,
但我有时也会觉得幸好有去改变
We wouldn't see Avancia so lively and bustling now
毕竟如果一直保持原状
if we had stayed the same.
就看不到现在这般 充满朝气的阿凡锡亚
That's why I think
所以我认为啊
it's important to enjoy the change.
能享受变化才是最重要的
I've always thought it's best to keep things the way they are.
我一直都觉得 永远维持现状才是最好的
And I still do.
就连现在也是
Honestly, I'm weaker than Lily.
老实说 我比莉莉懦弱多了
Of course, I want to support her…
我当然也想为那孩子加油
But watching Lily drift away from me makes me feel a little lonely.
但看着莉莉逐渐离我远去 让我觉得有些寂寞
Compared to Lily who wants to be independent,
比起想从姐姐身边独立的莉莉
Lilia, who can't be apart from her sister, might find it harder.
无法离开妹妹的莉莉亚
Some things might change,
虽然有些事情改变了
but I think
但是我认为
you and Lily will always be the same.
莉莉亚和莉莉肯定不会有所改变
You two will always be close and love each other.
我觉得你们今后 也会一直像现在这样相亲相爱
Even if some things change,
就算某些地方改变了
the important things won't.
但根本的部分是不会改变的吧
So, even if other things change,
所以就算其他地方变了
you can still get along like you do now.
你们还会像现在这样活下去
You're unexpectedly thoughtful.
你意外地考虑得挺多的嘛
Well, sorry. I was only saying what came to mind.
抱歉啊 我只说得出脑中想到的事
No, that'll do.
不 这样就够了
That's what I needed to hear.
而且正是我想听到的
Lily was shining so brightly today.
今天的莉莉太耀眼了
I couldn't look at her at all.
让我完全无法直视她
But…
不过呢
starting tomorrow, I will be watching her
明天开始我会好好看着 那孩子努力的身影
Go for it.
加油喔
I will.
我会加油的
Let's start from the 51st floor today.
那今天就从第51层开始吧
Lily, do the honors.
莉莉 拜托你了
Got it.
好的
The two major clans barely made it to the 51st floor.
由于两大战团才到51层
So we currently have no intel.
目前还没掌握到任何情报
However, the fog inside the labyrinth is thick.
但是迷宫里的雾很浓
We need to use other means to locate monsters besides detection magic.
我认为除了使用探知魔法之外
In that case, Lily will continue to use detection magic.
那莉莉就照样使用探知魔法
Marius and I will also search for monsters.
玛里乌斯和我 则在看得到的范围内寻找魔物
Luna, stay on alert at all times.
露娜也要随时保持警戒
Uh…
好的
A… About yesterday,
昨天的事是那个…
I didn't mean anything.
总之我没有其他意思！
Oh, okay.
这样啊
Seems like Luna's the type that won't black out even after drinking.
看来露娜是喝醉后也不会断片的人呢
Ready, everyone?
那么各位都准备好了吧？
Dungeon Walk.
迷宫传送！
KEILD LABYRINTH, 51ST FLOOR
（凯路德迷宫第51层）
The fog is really thick here.
这层的雾确实很浓厚呢
I don't think we can use detection magic in this area.
这里果然没办法使用探知魔法
Luna, can you try clearing the fog with wind magic?
露娜
Certainly.
好的
It didn't work.
不行啊
This fog
这阵雾恐怕是用魔力创造出来的
What?
什么？
That's why it won't disperse even if you use wind.
所以就算用风吹也吹不散
However, all monsters have some magic on them.
不过魔物身上总会有魔力
Just focus on detecting that energy.
只要专心探测魔力就可以了
I'll try.
我试试看
It's not exact, but I can vaguely sense it.
虽然不是很完美 但多少察觉得到
It's coming.
要来了！
Everyone, get back.
大家快退下！
Something's coming!
有东西在！
Water magic?
是水魔法啊？
This looks like…
这样看来…
The enemy is likely a Sahuagin!
对手应该是半鱼人！
I'll dispel them.
我来驱散！
It's too foggy. Our vision is obstructed.
雾实在太浓了 看不见敌人有些棘手呢
Everyone, move to the ten o'clock direction.
各位 逃到十点钟方向
There are no monsters there.
那边还没有被包围
We're counting on you.
交给你了
Taunt!
挑衅！
Finally coming out of the fog.
终于肯现身了啊
Just like Lily said.
跟莉莉说的一样 应该是半鱼人
Even if I can't see with my eyes, I can find you guys
凭我的探知能力 就算双眼变得看不到
by detecting your energy.
也能找到你们
Nice job, Marius.
干得好 玛里乌斯
After that,
接着我们渐渐掌握到玛里乌斯说的
and successfully defeated all the Sahuagin.
顺利打倒后来出现的半鱼人们
Let's take a break before heading to the next floor.
前往下一层前 先休息一下吧
I'll cook us something.
那我来煮个饭
-We'll help.
-我也来帮忙
You guys are going to eat the Sahuagin?
你们要吃半鱼人吗？
Yes.
对啊 得趁现在补充能量才行
Anyway,
话说回来
the items we got from this drop are quite something.
这次掉下来的素材全都很惊人呢
Right.
对啊
They are all high-quality stuff.
全是些高级品
I can look at Lily with no problems today.
我今天总算可以 像平时那样直视莉莉了
Thanks to our talk last night.
这都是因为昨天跟你聊过的关系
Thank you.
谢谢你
You two, the food is ready.
你们两个 饭煮好了！
Sahuagin tastes great!
半鱼人好好吃！
No fog here, but this place is spacious.
虽然没有雾 但这里很宽敞呢
Looks like a place where a boss would be.
简直就像头目的房间
Enemy approaching.
敌人好像来了
A magic circle?
魔法阵？
It's a Dark Skeleton.
是黑暗骷髅
There's something else too.
好像还有其他东西要现身
Something we haven't seen before.
是之前没看过的东西呢
Blue, red, yellow.
蓝色、红色、黄色
They look like crystals.
看起来就像水晶一样
Sacrificial Shield.
牺牲之盾！
Such a powerful aura.
好强大的威压
It's unlike any opponent
跟我们至今对战过的对手 完全不能相提并论
Lily, please give instructions.
莉莉 麻烦你下达指示
I'll start with physical attacks.
我先用撞击的方式攻击他
Understood.
好的
Taunt!
挑衅！
What?
这是什么？
It's the crystal.
是水晶
When Rud attacked, the yellow crystal unleashed
黄色的水晶随着路德发动攻击
a protective shield.
展开了类似防护罩的东西
This is a tricky foe.
真棘手啊
Should I distance myself for now?
要暂时拉开距离吗？
So the red one is offensive.
红色是用来攻击的吗？
Then, the blue one is…
那蓝色是…
Its movements became faster.
他的动作变快了
I see.
原来如此
The yellow one acts as a tank,
黄色会像肉盾一样进行防御
the blue one enhances abilities, and the red one is for magical attacks.
蓝色是强化能力
This is a tricky monster.
真是只难缠的魔物啊
The yellow defense crystal is the biggest problem.
其中黄色的防护罩是最棘手的
How should we attack?
该怎么进攻才好？
I'll attract its attention
把他的注意力吸引过来
and then attack from behind.
再从后方进行攻击！
Our attacks were blocked.
被挡下了
But it seems it can only deploy the shield around the crystals.
但他好像只能在水晶周围展开防护罩
Great, that'll work. Continue attacking it like this.
很好 行得通
A distraction?
是障眼法吗？
Is everyone all right?
大家没事吧？
Marius, what's wrong?
怎么了？玛里乌斯
I'm fine. It's Lilia…
我没事 是莉莉亚…
Something's not right with her.
莉莉亚看起来有些奇怪
Don't…
不准…
I must protect her.
我得保护她才行
Lily!
莉莉！
You've got me into trouble again. Lilia!
你又给我捅娄子
I have to protect her.
-莉莉亚！ -我得保护她才行
Don't bully Lily!
不准欺负莉莉
I will
莉莉就由我…
I'm your father.
我可是你老爸
What's with that look?
你那是什么眼神？
You guys are such an eyesore.
-你们真的很碍眼耶 -救救我们
I won't let you bully Lily anymore!
不准你再继续欺负莉莉！
Nin, heal her.
妮恩 快帮她恢复
Hold on.
等一下
Lily and Luna are afflicted too.
莉莉她们也陷入异常状态了
I have to heal them first.
我先治疗她们两个
Got it.
我知道了
I see.
原来如此
Only Marius, Nin, and I
有异常状态抗性的 只有我和玛里乌斯和妮恩
If the entire party falls into abnormal status, we'll be wiped out.
如果全员都陷入异常状态
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
You sent it flying with the crystals. Impressive.
居然能连同水晶把他揍飞 真有你的
Marius, can you hold the Dark Skeleton back?
玛里乌斯 你能负责压制黑暗骷髅吗？
Leave it to me. That thing's a lot easier to deal with.
交给我吧 那边好应付多了
Lilia!
莉莉亚！
I'm sorry, Lilia.
抱歉了 莉莉亚
I won't let you bully Lily anymore!
不准你再继续欺负莉莉！
Don't bully Lily!
不准欺负莉莉！
You said you were abandoned by your parents
你说你们被父母抛弃
and have been traveling on your own.
是靠互相扶持才走到现在的
Well, rather than say we were abandoned,
不
it would be more accurate to say we ran away because we were being abused.
正确来说其实是因为父母会虐待我们
Did the abnormal status trigger her past trauma?
难道她的异常状态
It's possible to calm down someone
我记得面对陷入恐慌状态的人
who's panicking by reassuring them with words
只要对她说出 能解除她恐惧根源的话语
that can dispel the cause.
就有机会恢复正常
Lilia,
莉莉亚
no one is going to hurt you here.
这里没有人会欺负你们！
Don't worry.
放心吧
You two are strong now.
你们已经变强了！
Ru… Rud?
路德？
That's right. It's me, Rud.
没错 我是路德
Everyone is here.
我和其他伙伴都在这里
So calm down.
所以冷静下来
No matter what happens, I'll do my best to protect you both.
不论发生什么事
The Dark Skeleton's magic must have thrown you into a state of confusion.
你应该是受到黑暗骷髅的魔法影响
Don't worry.
别担心
There's plenty of people
现在有很多人都会帮助你啊
Yeah. You're right.
是啊 你说得对
I have Rud and everyone else.
我现在有路德和其他伙伴了
Marius, thanks for holding it off.
玛里乌斯 辛苦你撑到现在
Take a break and get yourself healed.
暂时退下 去接受治疗吧
This is nothing.
这点程度根本不算什么
But roger that.
不过我就听你的吧
We won't be able to seriously damage it
果然如此 如果不先破坏掉黄色水晶
unless we destroy the yellow crystal.
就没办法痛快地打一场
But if we can break it,
不过反过来说 只要能突破那一点
we can finish this.
就没问题了吧
It's trying to trap me.
看来他不想让我冲上前
In that case…
既然如此…
Nin, I need your support.
妮恩 麻烦你了！
This will give me some protection from the fire magic.
这下就能稍微抵挡住火魔法了
Is there really no other way?
果然没辙了吗？
Lilia, Marius,
莉莉亚、玛里乌斯
I think I found an opening.
我好像找到突破方法了
The water droplets on my body went through its protective shield
刚才附着在我身上的水滴
I'm guessing this thing
我猜这家伙
can't resist both physical and magical attacks at once.
应该没办法同时抵挡魔法和物理攻击
The fire magic penetrated through the shield!
火魔法穿过防护罩了
This is payback for earlier.
这是你让我陷入恐慌状态的回礼
It blocked our attacks,
虽然被挡下了
but we managed to damage it.
但我们确实对他造成伤害了
Let's keep this up!
继续进攻吧
You won't get us with that trick again.
这边已经没有人会被那招影响了
Because I've used my magic
因为我用魔法
to nullify the effects of all abnormal statuses.
让异常状态无效化了
Luna's wind magic.
露娜的风魔法
Lily's fire magic.
莉莉的火魔法
It's incredible.
这场面真惊人
The yellow crystal is glowing!
黄色水晶发光了
It's trying to activate the shield and escape!
他打算展开防护罩逃跑
Rud?
路德？
You'll be damaged by our magic attacks.
你会被我们的魔法波及到的
I'll convert the damage
那些伤害
into power using Life Conversion.
正好可以用生命转换换成攻击力
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
It's been weakened.
他确实变虚弱了
It split into two!
居然分裂了
Even the crystals duplicated.
连水晶都变多了
Lilia, Marius,
莉莉亚、玛里乌斯
take one.
你们先帮我打倒一只
But we don't know which is the real one.
但是我不知道哪只才是真的
Either will do.
随便一只都可以
Rud won't be able to hold out much longer.
这样下去路德会撑不住的
That's the real one!
那一只是真的！
Its reaction is completely different from earlier.
他的动作跟刚才完全不一样
In that case…
那么…
This is the final blow.
这就是最后一击！
Marius, Lilia, take it down!
玛里乌斯、莉莉亚
I thought it was over for us
头目突然出现时
when the boss suddenly spawned.
我还以为完蛋了呢
Yeah.
是啊
Let's hurry up and find the magic circle
赶紧找到魔法阵
and rest before we get to the next floor.
在前往下一层前 先休息吧
I'll use my detection magic to find it.
那我用探知魔法找
It's not foggy here, so it should work.
这里的雾不浓 应该行得通
That's strange.
-奇怪 -怎么了？
I can't locate the magic circle.
我找不到魔法阵
I can't sense it at all.
一点气息都没有
Is this the final floor?
难道这里就是最底层了吗？
Marius, what do you think?
玛里乌斯 你怎么看？
Honestly, I haven't the faintest clue what the guardian here is trying to do.
老实说啊
Maybe that Dark Skeleton was their masterpiece
搞不好刚才那只 黑暗骷髅就是他的完美杰作
and seeing us defeat it scared them off.
看到我们将他打败 守护者就怕到不敢出来了
So they sealed off the way to stop us from advancing?
所以才把下一层的通道封起来吗？
Yes.
没错
I don't think this is an ordinary guardian we're dealing with.
我觉得这里的守护者应该不是普通人
So this is as far as we can go?
也就是说 我们只能攻略到这里吗？
Still, we've made it far enough.
不过目前的战绩应该已经够了
Let's head back for now.
还是先回去吧
Aw.
什么嘛
Are you already turning back?
你们要回去了吗？
Who's there?
是谁？
She's emitting such an intense aura… Who is this girl?
这个散发着奇妙压迫感的 少女是怎么回事？
Rud, this is bad!
路德 大事不妙了！
Oh, dear.
搞什么？
Did I set it so that Dark Skeletons would continue to spawn?
这里的设定 是会继续出现黑暗骷髅吗？
"Set"?
“设定”？
If four of them attack at once…
在这边一次遭到四只攻击的话…
I thought I'd already disabled that.
我应该已经删掉了啊
In one hit…
居然一击就打倒了
I didn't expect
没想到居然会出现魔王等级的守护者